Speaker: The concept is simple: Pick up your wallet. You’re ready.
Open the door, step out…and begin.
(This sentence, by the way, is the hardest thing you will read in this entire book.)
Then jump on a train. I’d suggest doing this microadventure by bike,
because you can explore so much more new ground that way,
but going by foot is a simple alternative. Hell, take a canoe if you like.
Anyway, choose a station, almost at random, that’s about 30 miles away from your home.
Buy a one-way ticket.
I say 30 miles because it’s a distance long enough to be challenging on a bike,
but achievable in one day, even if you are pretty unfit.
If you’re on foot, or if you can’t manage 30 miles, then do a shorter trip.
But don’t just duck out and do no trip! This approach applies throughout this book:
if something I suggest is too difficult, do an easier version.
If something is too easy, make it harder. Mould it and adapt it to your own situation.
Just make sure you do something.
When you arrive at your destination, hop on your bike and cycle home.
Travelling 30 miles away from your home should guarantee
that you’ll begin the adventure in lovely countryside.
I suggest you navigate homewards using a compass,
or the Crowsflight app on your smartphone, rather than a map.
A compass (or the app) won’t tell you what route to take,
it will only point you in the right direction.
The twists and turns and decisions that crop up along the way are
therefore down to your instinct and serendipity.
It becomes more of a journey into the unknown
than merely following the clearly prescribed route back home that a map would give you.
If that feels a bit daunting, by all means use a map or even a satnav.
Don’t let any of the ideas in this book put you off! Just modify them to what appeals to you.
I once spent four years cycling back home.
Within the single day ahead of you will lie most of the challenges, hurdles and rewards,
of a multi-year ride – although maybe fewer bears. But I mean this seriously.
You will have to navigate your way,
you’ll become wildly hungry and relish the joy of stopping at a café and eating cake, guilt free.
You will see things you have never seen before.
If you travel slowly and with a smile on your face, then you will meet different people,
have interesting conversations and learn something new about the world and about yourself.
When you eventually make it back to your front door, you’ll be tired, aching and hungry.
But you will have had an unusual and rewarding day and – I sincerely hope
– you will have realized that you are capable of more and are thus eager for more.
You have opened the door to adventure.